<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="28"><page Index="1" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[                    2021 WOMEN OF COLOR and The FIGHT For The VOTE
                       ]]></page><page Index="2" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  KEY TO COVER IMAGES: From Top Left (clockwise): Sojourner Truth, Harriet Tubman, Ida B. Wells, Frances E.W. Harper, Zitkála-Šá, Mary McLeod Bethune, Mary Church Terrell, Founders of the National Association of Colored Women (NACW, 1896), Founders of the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Inc® (1908), Founders of the Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc (1913), Nannie Helen Burroughs, Ida B. Wells in 1913 Suffrage Parade, Adelina Otero-Warren, Dr. Dorothy Height, NACW marching at The White House (1946), Women marching at the March on Washington (1963), Rep. Shirley Chisholm (1972), Fannie Lou Hamer, Sen. Carol Moseley Braun, Stacey Abrams (2020), and Vice President-elect Kamala Harris (center).
PHOTO CREDITS: We appreciate all of the individuals and organizations who provided photographs and images for Women of Color and the Fight for the Vote: Alabama Department of Archives and History (Apr); Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Inc (Cover); AP Images (Jun); AP Photo/Wilfredo Lee (Jan); Austin History Center, Austin Public Library. University of Texas (Apr); Baltimore Sun Media/Amy Davis (Intro); Sen Carol Moseley Braun (Cover); Collection of the U.S. House of Representatives (Cover, Sep); Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc (Cover, Nov); Elijah Nouvelage (Jan); Frederic J. Brown/AFP via Getty Images (Oct); George Grantham Bain Collection/Library of Congress (Cover, Mar, Oct); Library of Congress (Cov, Feb, Mar, Jul); Library of Congress/Carl Van Vechten Collection (Jun); Lyndon Baines Johnson Library and Museum (Aug); Mario Eugene Page (Nov); Marion County Voter Guide, 1952 (Feb); Metropolitan Museum of Art (Feb); MomsRising (Oct); Moorland-Spingarn Research Center, Manuscript Division Howard University (Jul); National Archives (Jun, Aug); National Archives/Rowland Scherman (Jun); National Association of Colored Women’s Clubs, Inc (Cover, Jul); National Portrait Gallery (Cover); New York Public Library Digital Collections (Feb); New York Public Library Digital Collections (Feb); New York Times OTD (Aug); Newsweek (May); Oakland Museum of California (Cover); Project Gutenberg (Feb); Public Domain/Gertrude Käsebier (May); Public Domain (The Crisis) (Feb); Public Domain/Newseum (Feb); Public Domain, The California Eagle (Feb); Public Domain, The Chicago Defender (Feb); Scripps College/Women’s Suffrage and Equal Rights Collection. Ella Strong Denison Library (Oct); Sharon Famer (Nov); Stacey Abrams (Cover, Apr); State Library and Archives of Florida (Cover); Toni L. Sandys/The Washington Post (Cover); US Department of Education (Nov); U.S. House of Representatives, Office of Terri Sewell (Nov); US House of Representatives, Official Websites (Sep, Dec); U.S. Senate, Official Websites (Dec); U.S, Senate Historical Office (Sep); University of Chicago Library (Apr); UTSA Libraries, Special Collections (Oct); Wikimedia Commons (Cover, Feb); Wikimedia, Women of Distinction (Feb); and Wikimedia/Warren K. Leffler (Cover).
]]></page><page Index="3" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Introduction
When Senator Kamala Harris is declared Vice President-elect of the United States on November 7, 2020, she is the first woman, the first Black woman, and the first Asian-American woman to win this office. In her acceptance speech, she acknowledges “the generations of women, Black women, Asian, white, Latina, Native American women—who throughout our nation’s history have paved the way for this moment tonight—all the women who have worked to secure and protect the right to vote for over a century.”
This calendar is dedicated to all of the women who have fought for the vote for all Americans. It focuses on the Black women and other women of color whose contributions to the achievement of the vote have not received full recognition or the place in history that they deserve. Women who:
• From the 1830s, travel widely advocating for abolition, suffrage, and other causes. Use their voices as preachers and orators; writers, poets, and publishers; and educators.
• Organize—working through churches, clubs, and local groups; forming national organizations, like the National Association of Colored Women (NACW), and sororities; and fighting for social justice for their communities.
• Take to the streets and make their protests public. NACW founder and first President Mary Church Terrell; the Delta Sigma Theta Sorority; members of the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority; Ida B. Wells, founder of Chicago’s Alpha Suffrage Club; and other women of color march in the suffrage parade of 1913 in Washington, DC.
• Work in the Civil Rights Movement through churches and organizations such as the Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC). For example, Septima Clark worked with the SCLC to establish more than 800 citizenship education schools.
• Register to vote, vote, register others, serve as poll watchers, and work as electors (below).
• Run for office—and win. Shirley Chisholm is the first Black woman in the House of Representatives and then the first Black woman to run for a major party’s nomination for President. She is emblematic of women on the local, state, and national levels, who not only vote, but also seek and gain public office.
This 2021 calendar* illustrates this story through the lives of some of these sheroes, but cannot begin to capture even a fraction of the women who write and speak, organize, march, protest, carry signs, make phone calls, tweet, knock on doors, write letters, register, vote, run for office, win, and represent all of us. It is thanks in no small part to the cumulative efforts of all of these women over nearly 200 years, that a record number of people (more than 159 million) vote in 2020 and elect a woman of color to the second highest office in this land.
*This calendar follows Women and the Vote: Centennial Calendar, WNDC Educational Foundation.
  ]]></page><page Index="4" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  ]]></page><page Index="5" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  JANUARY 2021
In January 2019, Senator Kamala Harris (above) launches her presidential campaign from Oakland, California, where she was born, the daughter of immigrants. She is not the first woman of color to run for the Presidential nomination of a major party—both Rep. Shirley Chisholm and Sen. Patsy Mink run in 1972 for the Democratic nomination. But Sen. Harris is the first woman of color to be put on the ticket of a major party as candidate for Vice President—and certainly the first to win. More than 81 million Americans vote for her and President-elect Joe Biden, the largest number of votes ever cast for a Presidential ticket.
 SUNDAY
MONDAY
TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
 “I may be the first woman member of Congress, but I won’t be the last.”
Rep. Jeanette Rankin, 1917
“. . . while I may be the first woman in this office, I won’t be the last.”
Vice President-elect Kamala Harris, 2020
  1 NewYear’sDay
  2
  3
  4
  5
   6
   7
  8
  9
   10
1918 Woman Suffrage Amendment passes House
11
  12
 13
1913 Delta Sigma Theta Sorority founded
 14
 15
1908 Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority founded
 16
1919 18th Amendment ratified prohibiting “intoxicating liquors”
1920 Zeta Phi Beta Sorority founded
 17
 18 Martin Luther King, Jr. Day
 19
  20 InaugurationDay
  21
  22
  23
1964 24th Amendment ratified abolishing poll taxes
 24
31
   25
 26
 27
  28
1895 Phyllis Wheatley Club founded
    29
    30
           ]]></page><page Index="6" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[           BLACK HISTORY MONTH
         ]]></page><page Index="7" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  FEBRUARY 2021
From the 1830s, women of color preach, speak, and write on abolition, women’s rights, and other issues. Maria Stewart is the first to speak to mixed audiences; (clockwise, from bottom) Jarena Lee preaches on the evils of slavery; Sojourner Truth is a noted speaker; Frances Harper is a poet, author, and orator; Mary Ann Shadd Cary (not shown) publishes The Provincial Freeman; Anna Julia Cooper pens A Voice from the South; Ida B. Wells writes and lectures on lynching; and Josephine St. Pierre Ruffin publishes The Woman’s Era and issues “the Call,” leading to the NACW. Building on 19th century Black press, the NAACP’s journal, The Crisis (below), covers woman’s suffrage and the Chicago Defender chronicles The Great Migration (1920). Charlotta Bass is a passionate activist and journalist who publishes the California Eagle and, in 1952, is the first woman of color to run for Vice President.
 SUNDAY
 MONDAY
 TUESDAY
  WEDNESDAY
  THURSDAY
  FRIDAY
 SATURDAY
     1
 2
 3
1870 15th Amendment ratified
 4
 5
 6
   7
  8
  9
  10
  11
  12
1909 National Association for the Advancement of Colored People founded
  13
1893 Ida B. Wells details horrors of lynching to white audience in Boston
   14 DouglassDay
  15
  16
  17
  18
  19
  20
   21
  22
  23
  24
  25
   26
   27
1922 Supreme Court upholds 19th Amendment as constitutional
    28
           “If the first woman God ever made was strong enough to turn the world upside down all alone, these women together ought to be able to turn it back, and get it right side up again!”
“Win or lose, we win by raising the issues.”
Sojourner Truth Charlotta Bass
       ]]></page><page Index="8" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[     WOMEN’S HISTORY MONTH
]]></page><page Index="9" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  MARCH 2021
On March 3, 1913, thousands of suffragists march down Pennsylvania Avenue supporting a suffrage amendment to the Constitution. Despite being refused or relegated to the back by white organizers, Black suffragists insist on marching. Ida B. Wells marches with the Illinois delegation (above). Delta Sigma Theta, in its first public act, Mary Church Terrell (below, left), members of Alpha Kappa Alpha and the NACW, and other Black women march with delegations of students, states, and professional groups. Organizers are more welcoming to other suffragists of color: Marie Louise Bottineau Baldwin (bottom, 1st and 2nd from left) is asked to create a float for Native women in costume; she opts for modern dress and marches with fellow lawyers. Mabel Ping-Hua Lee (bottom right) rides horseback in a 1912 New York parade and joins the 1913 parade on a Chinese float. Maria de Guadalupe Evangelina Lopez (not pictured) is asked to represent California; it is unknown if she attended.
 SUNDAY
 MONDAY
 TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
     1
  2
  3
1913 Suffrage parade in Washington, DC
 4
   5
  6
   7
 8
 9
 10
11
  12
 13
 14
  15
  16
  17
 18
   19
  20
 21
  22
  23
  24
1853 First issue of The Provincial Freeman published
 25
   26
  27
 28
   29
1961 23rd Amendment: DC residents can vote in presidential elections
  30
1952 Progressive Party nominates Charlotta Bass for Vice President, the first Black woman to run
 31
               ]]></page><page Index="10" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[    ]]></page><page Index="11" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  APRIL 2021
On November 2, 1920, barely 2 months after the enactment of the 19th Amendment, 8 million women vote in the 34th presidential election (Ida B. Wells runs for delegate in 1928). But, while national law changes, many practices do not; women of color, especially Black women in the South, find their ability to vote depressed by state and local laws, such as literacy requirements, poll taxes, white primaries, as well as by violence. Poll taxes and other barriers to voting are not prohibited until the mid-1960s, with the enactment of the 24th Amendment and the sweeping reforms of the Voting Rights Act of 1965. Still, in 2020, voter suppression remains an issue. Stacey Abrams (below) and many others work in Georgia to protect the voting rights of people of color and young people, and help register nearly 800,000 voters for the 2020 presidential election.
 SUNDAY
 MONDAY
 TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
       1
  2
  3
   4
 5
 6
1917 US enters World War I
 7
 8
 9
1865 Civil War ends
 10
 11
  12
1861 Civil War begins; suffrage activity suspended
  13
  14
.
  15
  16
  17
 18
.
  19
1929 Literate Puerto Rican women gain vote
  20
  21
  22
  23
  24
 25
   26
  27
  28
  29
  30
         ]]></page><page Index="12" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[    ]]></page><page Index="13" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  MAY 2021
At the 1848 meeting at Seneca Falls, NY, white suffragists are inspired by local Iroquois women who own property, have rights to their children, and exercise political power. Zitkála-Šá (above) and other Native activists advocate for suffrage. However, Native women are not considered US citizens and cannot vote until the passage of the Indian Citizenship Act of 1924. Even with citizenship, many still face state and local barriers to voting. Zitkála-Šá founds the National Council of American Indians in 1926 to advocate for rights and representation. Not until 2018 are the first Native women elected to Congress: Representatives Deb Haaland (NM, below) and Sharice Davids (KS). In 2020, Rep. Haaland is nominated Secretary of Interior and is thus slated to become the first Native American to serve as a Cabinet Secretary.
 SUNDAY
MONDAY
TUESDAY
WEDNESDAY
THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
 “In the councils of the Iroquois every adult male or female had a voice upon all questions brought before it,”
Elizabeth Cady Stanton
“Division of power between the sexes in this Indian Republic was nearly equal...its women exercised controlling power in peace and war.”
“Never was justice more perfect, nor civilization higher.”
Matilda Gage
    1
  2
 3
 4
  5
  6
 7
 8
 9
1865 Sojourner Truth addresses American Equal Rights Association, sings “We Are Going Home”
 10
1886 Frances Harper: “White women speak of rights; I speak of wrongs”
 11
  12
  13
  14
  15
 16
 17
1954 Brown v Board of Education rules school segregation illegal
 18
1896 Plessy v Ferguson rules “separate but equal” is constitutional
  19
  20
  21
  22
 23
30
   24
 25
 26
  27
    28
    29
1851 Sojourner Truth delivers “Ain’t I a Woman” speech
in Ohio
    Memorial Day 31
       ]]></page><page Index="14" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[    ]]></page><page Index="15" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  JUNE 2021 In April 1939, Marian Anderson gives a concert to an integrated audience of 75,000 at the Lincoln Memorial in the segregated city of Washington, DC (above). Both Mary McLeod Bethune, President of the new National Council of Negro Women (below, left), and future President Dorothy Height (below, right) attend. Dr. Height recalls, “The first words that came from her mouth were, ‘My country tis of thee. . . .’ She made us all proud to be Americans when she could sing . . . ‘let freedom ring.’” President Bethune recalls, “Something happened in all of our hearts. . . . We are on the right track—we must go forward. The reverence and concentration of the throngs told a story of hope for tomorrow—a story of pulling together—a story of splendor and real democracy.” 24 years later, Dr. Height is one of the organizers of the March on Washington
where Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. shares his dream and inspires the next generation of civil rights workers.
 SUNDAY
 MONDAY
 TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
     1
  2
1924 Indian Citizenship Act grants citizenship to Native Americans
  3
  4
1919 After 41 years of debate, Senate passes Woman Suffrage amendment
  5
   6
 7
 8
 9
 10
 11
 12
 13
  14
  15
  16
  17
  18
  19
Juneteenth celebrates emancipation from slavery
 20
  21
  22
  23
  24
  25
  26
 27
1952 Immigration and Naturalization Act lets Asians become citizens
  28
   29
  30
              ]]></page><page Index="16" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[     ]]></page><page Index="17" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  JULY 2021
In 1896, 73 delegates found the National Association of Colored Women (NACW) in Washington, DC, including Mary Church Terrell (1st president), Josephine St. Pierre Ruffin, Harriet Tubman, Ida B. Wells, Anna Julia Cooper, Fannie Barrier Williams, Hallie Q. Brown, Frances E. Harper, and Helen Pitts Douglass (Frederick Douglass’ widow). By 1914, NACW has 50,000 members and 1,000 clubs across the country focusing on the welfare of their communities and other social issues, including lynching, suffrage, and voter suppression. Activism continues under other leaders such as Nannie Helen Burroughs, Fannie Coppin, and Mary McCleod Bethune (President) who later founds the National Council of Negro Women (1935). For example, NACW issues an anti-lynching pamphlet (1922) and protests lynching at the White House (1946) (see above). In 1952, 88-year- old Mary Church Terrell pickets segregated restaurants in Washington, leading to a 1953 ruling declaring segregated eating places unconstitutional. NACW is renamed National Association of Colored Women’s Clubs, Inc. in 1958.
 SUNDAY
MONDAY
TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
   “And so, lifting as we climb, onward and upward we go, struggling and striving, and hoping that the buds and blossoms of our desires will burst into glorious fruition ‘ere long.”
Mary Church Terrell
    1
1971 26th Amendment: Congress lowers the voting age to 18
  2
1964 Civil Rights Act enacted
  3
   4 Independence Day
 5
 6
 7
 8
 9
1868 14th Amendment ratified extending citizenship and rights to former slaves
 10
 11
 12
  13
  14
  15
  16
  17
 18
  19
1848 Seneca Falls Conven- tion endorses Declaration of Sentiments
  20
  21
1896 National Association of Colored Women founded, 1st national organization for women of color
  22
  23
  24
 25
  26
   27
  28
  29
1895 Josephine Ruffin calls for a “new era” for the colored women of America
  30
   31
      ]]></page><page Index="18" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[    ]]></page><page Index="19" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  AUGUST 2021
Even with passage of the 19th Amendment, many women still cannot vote because of state and local laws and practices. In 1965, the Voting RightsActprohibitspracticesorproceduresthat “...denyorabridgetherightofanycitizenoftheUnitedStatestovoteonaccountofrace or color.” The Act has a dramatic impact—significantly increasing voter registration and participation, among Blacks, in the Southern states, and especially among minority women. Above, voters line up at a small country store in Peachtree, AL to vote in May 1966. Below, President Lyndon Johnson, after signing the Act, greets honored guests, including Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. and Rosa Parks, who in 1955 had refused to give up her seat on a Montgomery, AL bus, a critical catalyst to the Civil Rights Movement.
 SUNDAY
 MONDAY
 TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
  1
  2
  3
  4
  5
  6
1965 Voting Rights Act signed into law
  7
   8
 9
 10
 11
 12
 13
 14
 15
 16
 17
  18
  19
  20
  21
 22
 23
 24
1848 Lucretia Mott writes to the Liberator about her visit to the Seneca Nation
  25
  26
1920 19th Amendment declared properly ratified, becomes law
  27
  28
1986 Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act passed
 29
 30
1835 Abolitionist Sara Grimke publishes letter on Boston slavery riot
 31
     .
          ]]></page><page Index="20" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[    ]]></page><page Index="21" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  SEPTEMBER 2021
Firsts! In 1916, Jeannette Rankin (MT) is the first woman elected to the House of Representatives. Not until 1964, is the first minority woman, Japanese-American Patsy Mink (HI), elected to the House (below, left). In 1968, Shirley Chisholm (IL) is the first Black woman elected to the House and both she and Patsy Mink seek the Democratic nomination for President in 1972. Rep. Chisholm’s portrait (above) hangs in the Capitol. In 1989, Ileana Ros-Lehtinen (FL) is the first Cuban-American and first Latina elected to the House (below, center). In 1992, Carol Moseley Braun (IL) (below, right) is the first Black woman elected to the Senate (the second African-American since Reconstruction). In 2018, Sharice Davids (KS) and Deb Haaland (NM) (lower left, right) are the first Native women elected to the House—94 years after passage of the Indian Citizenship Act.
 SUNDAY
 MONDAY
 TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
         1
  2
  3
  4
   5
 6 Labor Day
 7
 8
 9
 10
 11
 12
   13
   14 .
   15
   16
   17
1789 US Constitution signed; states keep authority to decide who can vote
   18
   19
 20
 21
 22
 23
 24
1875 Matilda Gage writes about Five Nations confeder- acy where women “exercise power in peace and war”
 25
  26
   27
  28
  29
  30
           ]]></page><page Index="22" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  ]]></page><page Index="23" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  OCTOBER 2021
Since at least the 1910s, Latinas have been actively engaged in suffrage activities (below). In California, material on voting is translated into Spanish. In New Mexico, suffragist Nina Otero-Warren (below, left) and others work with the National Woman’s Party, and in Texas, journalist Jovita Idár (below, right) writes against “Juan Crow laws” and encourages women’s education and suffrage. Otero-Warren runs for Congress in 1922. She loses and not until 67 years later is Ileana Ros-Lahtinen (FL) elected to the House. Later activism focuses heavily on labor issues; activist Dolores Huerta joins Cesar Chavez to found the United Farm Workers. Huerta continues work on voter registration and participation—even celebrating her 90th birthday in 2020 promoting the vote (above).
 SUNDAY
 MONDAY
 TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
          1
  2
   3
 4
 5
 6
 7
 8
 9
 10
 11 IndigenousPeoples Day
 12
  13
  14
  15
  16
 17
 18
 19
  20
  21
  22
  23
 24
31
 25
 26
 27
  28
    29
1864 Sojourner Truth visits President Lincoln in the White House
    30
         ]]></page><page Index="24" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[             ]]></page><page Index="25" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  NOVEMBER 2021
Black women form clubs as early as 1793 and work to support their communities, abolition, suffrage, and other causes. Two Black sororities stand out for their work promoting the vote as well as their success in seeing their members elected. Alpha Kappa Alpha (1908) members—Sen. Kamala Harris and seven Representatives—stand in front of a statue honoring Rosa Parks in the Capitol (above, left). Seven Delta Sigma Theta (1913) members are Representatives (above, right). Dr. Height addresses AKA convention (below, left). At an annual conference, Delta Days (below, left), national members advocate for policies affecting their communities, meet members of Congress, and hone their political skills. Both sororities are committed to voter education, registration, and protection, and are effective users of social media (see the video “Stroll to the Polls” (below right)).
 SUNDAY
 MONDAY
 TUESDAY
 WEDNESDAY
 THURSDAY
 FRIDAY
SATURDAY
     1
  2
1920 Eight million women vote across the US
  3
  4
  5
  6
   7
 8
 9
 10
 11 VeteransDay 1918 World War I ends
 12
1922 Sigma Gamma Rho Sorority founded
 13
 14
  15
  16
  17
  18
  19
  20
 21
 22
  23
  24
  25 Thanksgiving Day
  26
  27
 28
  29
  30
                ]]></page><page Index="26" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[    WOMEN OF COLOR IN
 THE 117
 th CONGRESS
        Rep. Alma S. Adams – NC
Rep. Nanette Diaz Barragán – CA
Rep. Karen Bass – CA
Rep. Joyce Beatty – OH
Rep. Lisa Blunt Rochester – DE
Rep. Cori Bush - MO
Rep. Judy Chu – CA
Rep. Yvette D. Clarke – NY
        Rep. Sharice Davids – KS
Rep. Val Demings – FL
Rep. Veronica Escobar – TX
Rep. Marcia L. Fudge – OH
Rep. Sylvia R. Garcia – TX
Rep. Deb Haaland – NM
Rep. Jahana Hayes – CT
Rep. Jaime Herrera Beutler – WA
        Rep. Sheila Jackson Lee – TX
Rep. Pramila Jayapal – WA
Rep. Eddie Bernice Johnson – TX
Rep. Robin Kelly – IL
Rep. Young Kim – CA
Rep. Brenda L. Lawrence – MI
Rep. Barbara Lee – CA
Rep. Teresa Leger Fernandez – NM
        Rep. Nicole Malliotakis – NY
Rep. Doris Matsui – CA
Rep. Lucy McBath – GA
Rep. Grace Meng – NY
Rep. Gwen Moore – WI
Rep. Stephanie Murphy – FL
Rep. Grace F. Napolitano – CA
Rep. Alexandria Ocasio- Cortez – NY
        Rep. Ilhan Omar – MN
Rep. Ayanna Pressley – MA
Rep. Lucille Roybal- Allard – CA
Rep. Maria Salazar – FL
Rep. Linda T. Sánchez – CA
Rep. Terri A. Sewell – AL
Rep. Michelle Steel – CA
Rep. Marilyn Strickland – WA
        Rep. Rashida Tlaib – MI
Rep. Norma J. Torres – CA
Rep. Lauren Underwood – IL
Rep. Nydia M. Velázquez – NY
Rep. Maxine Waters – CA
Rep. Bonnie Watson Coleman – NJ
Rep. Nikema Williams – GA
Rep. Frederica S. Wilson – FL
                                                         ]]></page><page Index="27" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  DECEMBER 2021
The 117th Congress opens with 48 Representatives and 4 Senators who identify themselves as women of color (24 Black, 13 Latina, 9 Asian, 2 Native, and 4 multi-racial).* ** There are also 4 women of color who are non-voting Delegates to the House, including Del. Eleanor Holmes Norton, who has represented DC for 30 years. The road is long, but reflects progress toward a representative and diverse US Congress and the enormous efforts of women over nearly 200 years to enfranchise all women.
* Including Sen. Harris who is Vice President-elect and, according to the Constitution, serves as President of the Senate (see cover).
** Data from the Center for American Women in Politics, Eagleton Institute of Politics, Rutgers University. https://cawp.rutgers./women-in-117th-congress. Based on data provided by Congresswomen to CAWP.
      SUNDAY
MONDAY
TUESDAY
WEDNESDAY
THURSDAY
FRIDAY
SATURDAY
        Sen. Catherine Cortez Masto – NV
Sen. Tammy Duckworth – IL
Sen. Mazie K. Hirono – HI
1
1833 Philadelphia Female Anti-Slavery Society founded by biracial group of suffragists
2
3
4
                  5
1935 National Council of Negro Women founded
6
7
1868 Universal suffrage amendment introduced in Senate; never voted on
8
9
10
11
             12
13
14
15
16
17
1943 Chinese Exclusion Act repealed
18
             19
20
21
22
23
24
25 Christmas Day
           28
29
30
31
Del. Eleanor Holmes Norton - DC
            26 27
 ]]></page><page Index="28" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[  Acknowledgements
      Dr. Arthelda Busch Williams (National Historian, NACWC)
Martha Perine Beard, Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Inc®
Dr. Thelma Daley, 16th President, Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Inc
Farar Elliott, US House of Representatives
Sabrina Evans, Center for Black Digital Research, #DigBlk.
Jessica Claire Haney
Chelsea Hill, Center for American Women and Politics,
Eagleton Institute, Rutgers State University Judy Hubbard
Dr. Pamela R. Johnson (Editor)
Rempee Kalia
Dr. Shirley Moody-Turner, Center for Black Digital
Research, #DigBlk.
Heather Moore, US Senate Historical Office Rosalyn Overstreet-Gonzalez
Dr. Alison Parker
Dr. Carol L. Rogers
Claire Sandberg
Winfield Swanson
Laura Whitaker
Amelia Whitfield
Renée Winfield (Designer)
Patricia Wirth, Turning Point Suffrage Memorial
Suzanne Finney Patricia Fitzgerald Dr. Jo Freeman Amanda Gallagher Katherin Golitzen
Published by the WNDC Educational Foundation www.WNDCEducationalFoundation.org
© Copyright 2020
  ]]></page></pages></Search>